Christopher Glinka

Jr. Software Developer & Systems Analyst

Contact

Edmonton, AB (587) 778 8210

glinkachris@gmail.com

Profiles

Portfolio: <u>cglinkadesigns.com</u> LinkedIn: Christopher Glinka

GitHub: CGlinka95

Key Skills

Educational & Team Leadership
Interpersonal Communication
Mentorship
Project Management
Project Planning
Problem Solving
Version Control

GitHub

JavaScript React

C#

.Net Core

SQL

Linq

Java

HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

Node.js

Python

Summary

A motivated Software Developer with three years of technical education from NAIT's DMIT program, complemented by a BA in English from Concordia University of Edmonton. With a lifelong passion for technology and a strong desire for continuous learning, this individual transitioned to the IT field. Their role at Code Ninjas sparked a newfound love for teaching kids coding and active involvement in community events like Big Brothers Big Sisters, Autism Edmonton, and Ukrainian Refugee fundraisers. They also lead a weekly teen-night at Code Ninjas, providing a space for like-minded individuals to connect, explore interests, and learn together.

Experience

React Web Portfolio • cglinkadesigns.com

I developed a personalized website to showcase my identity, expertise, and coding skills.

Technologies used include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and EmailJS. The project is accessible on various devices and is deployed and hosted under my own domain using hostinger.com. It was an enjoyable project that provided valuable learning experiences in areas like state management, hooks, APIs (such as EmailJS), and deployment. Additionally, the website showcases other projects I'm particularly proud of, which can also be explored and viewed.

October 2021 - September 2023

Summer Camp Director & Supervisor • Code Ninjas, St. Albert I created and cultivated an engaging and educational experience for young learners, aged 5 - 16. I lead a team of instructors, oversaw center operations, and ensured kids had a safe, enjoyable, and enriching experience while exploring the world of coding and technology.

- In a leadership role at Code Ninjas St. Albert, I played a key role in achieving record-breaking results during our grand opening. We secured over 70 student sign-ups before opening day and quickly reached a milestone, breaking even, and surpassing 120 active accounts within just three months of operation.
- I received the 'Got Yo' Back' award for consistently going the extra mile, helping beyond regular duties, maintaining unwavering

reliability, and actively participating in various events and volunteer initiatives, contributing to both company growth and community engagement.

 I led the successful launch of a new curriculum and software developed by Code Ninjas in collaboration with Microsoft. The project started in April 2023 and was completed by the end of May 2023.
 This involved updating and organizing equipment to ensure a smooth transition for children, designing a training program for instructors to gain hands-on experience, and effectively communicating the changes to parents.

July 2021 – November 2021 Barista • Starbucks, Namao, Edmonton

January 2014 – March 2020 Senior Sales Associate & Key-holder • GameStop, St. Albert

Education

September 2020 – April 2023

DMIT • Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

Graduated | Computer Software Development

- Dean's Honor Roll 2021, 22 & 23
- I led a team of four Software Developers for our Capstone project, finishing the Beta version of a .NET Core educational platform simulating Upstream Oil & Gas trading for CanAfrica. Collaborating with a Business Analyst, we regularly met with the company's chair to align with their vision, meet goals, enhance functionality, and adhere to tight deadlines. We competed against another team of four developers on the same project to deliver the closest version to the client's vision. After presenting our final product to the client, our team was selected for having a more streamlined, user-friendly, functional, and intuitive application. We were then given the opportunity to showcase it to NAIT faculty, alumni, and industry professionals.
 - I had a specific role on the team, which involved overseeing our Git branches, minimizing merge conflicts, and maintaining the main/production branch to ensure its functionality. I regularly communicated with team members to ensure their smooth progress and assisted in resolving any issues or blockers they encountered.
 - I dedicated a significant portion of my time to the backend of our stack. My responsibilities included ensuring user-friendly CRUD page navigation, maintaining clean and accurate data processing in our database, and implementing additional

features like breadcrumbs, simulation activities, and security measures to prevent issues like over-posting and mass assignment, which are akin to smaller-scale Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks.

 During the final week of the semester, I helped another developer deploy our completed application on the DMIT Student Server. This allowed others to access and test the application through a web browser, facilitating our presentation process.

September 2016 – April 2020
Bachelor of Arts • Concordia University of Edmonton
Graduated | English Major | Psychology Minor

 Achieved excellence in collaborative research projects, demonstrating proficiency in conveying data and vital information effectively through written reports and presentations.

References

Dan Mouris • NAIT Instructor

Email: dmouris@nait.ca

Shannon Stevenson • Director of Operations and Owner of Code

Ninjas St. Albert & Windermere

Phone: (825) 440 5485

Email: shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com

Annabelle Syms • Director of Customer Service at Code Ninjas

Windermere

Phone: (780) 236 1536

Email: annabelle.syms@gmail.com